citizencorps.gov 2004-06-07

# Citizen Corps: Viewer Privacy and Security Policy

### Citizen Corps Viewer Privacy and Security Policy

Thank you for visiting the Citizen Corps website and reviewing our privacy and security policy. Our privacy policy is clear - we do not collect any personal information about you without your knowledge.

This website is provided as a public service by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, FEMA. Information presented on this site is considered public information and may be distributed or copied. Use of appropriate byline/photo/image credits is requested. 

Information Collected on All Website Visits 

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically - but none of this information will identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit: 

  * The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website; 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site; 
  * The date and time you access our site; 
  * The pages you visit; and 
  * If you linked to the Citizen Corps website from another website, the address of that website. 

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to our site, to determine what information is of most and least interest, to identify system performance or problem areas, and to help us in determining technical design specifications. Again, we do not track or record personal information about individuals and their visits without your knowledge. 

Information Collected from E-mails and Web Forms

If you choose to provide us with personal information by sending an e-mail or by filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it through our website, we will use this information to respond to your message and to help us provide you information that you request. We do not collect personal information for any other purpose. To better assist you, this information may also be shared with State and Local Citizen Corps Councils for the area in which you live and with organizations that manage the programs in which you have indicated an interest.

The information you provide is strictly not given to any private company or organization or to any private persons. This site also does not collect or use personal information for commercial marketing. 

And once again, we will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. For more information on the privacy act policy on the Citizen Corps individual database system of records, please read our Federal Register Notice. 

Links to Other Sites

The Citizen Corps website has links to the websites of many other federal agencies and not-for-profit organizations that support the Citizen Corps mission. In a few cases, we may also link to private organizations, with their permission. In all cases, you will be given clear indication that you are leaving the Citizen Corps website. Once you have linked to another site, you are then subject to the privacy policy of that site. 

Security and Intrusion Detection

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs software programs to monitor host and network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration guidelines. 

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act."
